{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "This man claimed that there is “simply no excuse for the mayhem that followed” the verdict in the Rodney King trial in his speech Reflections on Urban America. During one debate, this man criticized the book Earth in the Balance which had recently been released by his opponent. After claiming that a former President was a friend of his, Lloyd Bentsen told this man “Senator, you’re not Jack Kennedy.” For ten points, name this Vice President under George H.W. Bush.",
      "answer": "Dan Quayle"
    },
    {
      "question": "One artist from this country used floating geometric forms in his non-objective art and founded the Suprematist movement. Another artist used photomontage to show an oversized leader of this country speaking in front of industrial wires and phonograph-like speakers. Emigrants from this country to Munich, Germany founded the Blue Rider movement. A propagandistic “illustration” was created by Varvara Stepanova to represent a Five-Year Plan instituted in, for ten points, what home country of artists Kasimir Malevich and Wassily Kandinsky?",
      "answer": [
        "Russia",
        "Soviet Union",
        "USSR",
        "Union of Soviet Socialist Republics",
        "CCCP",
        "Soyuz Sovetskikh Sotsialisticheskikh Respublik"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Precedents for this Supreme Court case included Kirby v. Kirby and Kinney v. The Commonwealth. Robert McIlwaine represented the state party in this case using precedents like Naim v. Naim and Pace v. Alabama. The 9-0 ruling in this case held that anti-miscegenation laws violated the Equal Protection and Due Process Clauses. For ten points, name this landmark 1967 case that ended bans on interracial marriage.",
      "answer": "Loving v. Virginia"
    },
    {
      "question": "Walter Kauffman’s biography of this man argued that syphilis caused his end of life madness, which seemingly began with an 1889 incident in which he rushed to save a horse from being beaten on the streets of Turin. This thinker, who stated that the “abyss will gaze back into you” in Beyond Good and Evil, discussed the role of the Apollonian and the Dionysian in his The Birth of Tragedy. Nazi German philosophy was heavily influenced by, for ten points, what German author of Thus Spake Zarathustra?",
      "answer": "Frederich Nietzsche"
    },
    {
      "question": "Prior to this battle, Joachim Murat [yoh-ah-keem mu-rah] was admonished for declaring an armistice at Sch¨ongrabern [SCHUN-grah-bern] without his superior’s consent, giving the enemy time to join forces near Brno [BIR-no]. One general, who sought to begin this battle before the entrance of Prussia into the war, baited Franz von Weyrother’s [VIE-roh-ter’s] forces by abandoning the Pratzen Heights. The Treaty of Pressburg was signed after this battle, dissolving the Holy Roman Empire. For ten points, name this 1805 victory over the Third Coalition by Napoleon.",
      "answer": [
        "Battle of Austerlitz",
        "Battle of the Three Emperors"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In this state’s town of Gibsonton, a circus colony became a retirement community for performers, including Grady Stiles, the murdered “Lobster Boy.” The Gasparilla Pirate Festival is held in this state, which experienced an influx of immigration from the south through the Freedom Flights and the Mariel Boatlift. This state’s Tamiami Trail along much of Route 41 becomes Calle Ocho in the Little Havana neighborhood. For ten points, name this state where FDR was nearly assassinated in Bayfront Park in Miami.",
      "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man seized emergency powers after announcing the discovery of the Cohen Plan, a supposed communist plot against him. This ruler repressed his former supporters, the fascist Integralist movement, after banning all political parties. This man declared that he would “leave life to enter history” before shooting himself with a Colt pistol in 1954 to prevent a military coup. The Petrobras state monopoly on oil was created by, for ten points, what Estado Novo-era president of Brazil?",
      "answer": "Getulio Vargas"
    },
    {
      "question": "This piece includes a “shuffle” theme whose melody parallels that of its composer’s song “The Man I Love.” This piece, which was orchestrated by Ferde Grof´e [ferd gro-FAY], called for “vernacular instruments” such as a banjo. The “Train” theme in this piece was inspired by the “steely rhythms” of its composer’s train ride to Boston. This piece, commissioned for “An Experiment in Modern Music” by Paul Whiteman in 1924, begins with a 17-note clarinet glissando. For ten points, name this “jazz concerto” by George Gershwin.",
      "answer": "Rhapsody in Blue"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the prelude to this conflict, Jeffery Amherst heavily restricted the use of gunpowder. The Conestoga Massacre was carried out by the Paxton Boys in the aftermath of this conflict. Appalled by colonial behavior during this conflict, George III passed a law banning settlers from moving past the Appalachian Mountains. The Royal Proclamation of 1763 was passed in response to, for ten points, what rebellion led by a namesake Ottawa Chief?",
      "answer": "Pontiac’s Rebellion"
    },
    {
      "question": "This empire was ruled by the Asen Dynasty which came to power after Ivan Asen won a 7-year siege at Tarnovo. Basil II fought a series of wars against this empire, earning a nickname for slaying its people. A leader of this empire had the Peslav Literary School create the Cyrillic alphabet. Under the leadership of Simeon the Great, this empire fought the Magyars in several wars with neighboring Hungary. For ten points, name this empire that, in 809 AD, took control of Sofia.",
      "answer": "Bulgarian Empire"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A commission led by Robert La Follette Sr. began investigating this event after the ransacking of the Senate Office Building. The Supreme Court held that Congress had the power to compel testimony in McGrain v. Daugherty, which stemmed from Harry Daugherty’s failure to investigate the perpetrators of this event. During this scandal, Albert Fall leased public land owned by the Navy, such as Elk Hills, to private oil companies. For ten points, name this land scandal during the administration of Warren G. Harding.",
        "answer": "Teapot Dome scandal"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Albert Fall was able to carry out the Teapot Dome scandal by exploiting his authority in this position.",
        "answer": "Secretary of the Interior"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This figure names an effect in which the rate of fermentation increases with low levels of oxygen. This figure, who is credited with disproving spontaneous generation, saved the life of Joseph Meister by administering an invention of his, the rabies vaccine. Antoine van Leeuwenhoek and this man are considered the fathers of microbiology. For ten points, name this French scientist who names a process where heat is applied to destroy germs in milk.",
        "answer": "Louis Pasteur"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Louis Pasteur also invented a vaccine for this bacterial infection caused by the spores of a species of Bacillus, which were sent in letters to politicians in a late 2001 terrorist attack.",
        "answer": "anthrax"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This author’s How Many Subjects? Statistical Power Analysis in Research studied the social impact of hiding sexual orientation. Mark Judge denied “any memory [...] whatsoever” of a 1982 incident in which he stopped an altercation between this woman and her attacker, who served on the D.C. Circuit Court of Appeals until October 2018. For ten points, name this research psychologist from Stanford University who reported being sexually assaulted by Supreme Court justice Brett Kavanaugh.",
        "answer": [
          "Christine Blasey Ford",
          "either",
          "both last names"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Ford’s accusations were kept secret by this senator until The Intercept leaked that she was withholding a document on Kavanaugh, leading this senator to contact the FBI.",
        "answer": "Dianne Feinstein"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "During this conflict, the anarchist Nestor Mahkno seized control of an army due to a power vacuum caused by the fall of Hetman Skoropadsky’s government. Wrangel’s Fleet fled to occupied Constantinople at the end of the “southern” front of this conflict. American troops occupied Vladivostok during this conflict in support of Alexander Kolchak’s provisional government. For ten points, name this 1917 conflict between the Mensheviks and Bolsheviks for control of a European nation.",
        "answer": "Russian Civil War"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "During the Russian Civil War, a legion from this country captured an imperial gold reserve on the Trans-Siberian railway.",
        "answer": "Czechoslovakia"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In 1910, the mayor of this city, J. Barry Mahool, passed an ordinance barring blacks from moving into white majority areas such as the Eutaw Place neighborhood. This city was the site of the Pratt Street Riots where Union soldiers, en route to Camden Station, clashed with secessionists. In an invasion of this city, the British navy bombarded Fort McHenry, an attack that inspired Francis Scott Key to write the “Star-Spangled Banner.” For ten points, name this city which flourished as the busiest port in Maryland.",
        "answer": "Baltimore"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Pratt Street Riot was sparked by an angry mob composed of a faction of anti-war Democrats given this name. This faction was compared to a venomous snake by Republicans.",
        "answer": "Copperheads"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A general from this dynasty was able to escape charges of treason by removing his shirt to reveal a tattoo reading “serve the country with the utmost loyalty.” This dynasty was founded by Yuanlang who led a coup d’etat against Emperor Gong. This dynasty, the first to use paper money, is broken into Northern and Southern periods. Kublai Khan conquered, for ten points, what Chinese dynasty succeeded by the Yuan?",
        "answer": "Song"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Yuan conquered the Song at this 1279 naval battle despite being outnumbered 10 to 1.",
        "answer": [
          "Battle of Yamen",
          "Naval Battle of Mount Ya"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The “Dope Sheet” was a press release that this NFL team’s co-founder wrote in its first few seasons. This team won the 1967 NFL Championship game, which had a game-time temperature of negative 15 degrees and was known as the “Ice Bowl.” This team anchors the smallest market for any team in the four major American sports leagues. Vince Lombardi coached, for ten points, what publicly-owned NFL team that plays its home games at Lambeau Field in Wisconsin?",
        "answer": [
          "Green Bay Packers",
          "either underlined portion"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Lambeau Field is the largest stadium in Wisconsin; the second largest is this stadium at the University of Wisconsin. This stadium is named for a Union training camp that, itself, was named after a Wisconsin governor.",
        "answer": "Camp Randall Stadium"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "With Zionist Theodor Herzl, this man came up with the Uganga Scheme to temporarily make a Jewish homeland in Africa. This man gave the Mansion House speech denouncing Germany’s actions during the Agadir Crisis. With Woodrow Wilson, Vittorio Orlando, and George Clemenceau, this man made up the “Big Four” at the Versailles Peace Talks. For ten points, name this Welshman that served as the British PM during the second half of World War I.",
        "answer": "David Lloyd George"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Lloyd George served as Chancellor of the Exchequer under this Liberal UK Prime Minister who declared war on Germany after it violated Belgium’s neutrality.",
        "answer": "H.H. Asquith"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "United States Navy",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Type of ship that launches fighters, of which the United States have 11 of the total 41 in the world.",
          "answer": "aircraft carrier"
        },
        {
          "question": "Battleship that was sunk in the opening attack on Pearl Harbor and names a memorial in Hawaii.",
          "answer": "USS Arizona"
        },
        {
          "question": "Virginia city in Hampton Roads containing the world’s largest naval base.",
          "answer": "Norfolk"
        },
        {
          "question": "Series of conflicts that started after Thomas Jefferson refused to pay a bribe to pirates.",
          "answer": "Barbary Wars"
        },
        {
          "question": "Captain who may have said “I have not yet begun to fight!” aboard the Bon Homme Richard.",
          "answer": "John Paul Jones"
        },
        {
          "question": "Ship called “Old Ironsides” that still floats in Boston Harbor.",
          "answer": "USS Constitution"
        },
        {
          "question": "Commander in Chief of Pacific Ocean Areas in World War II.",
          "answer": "Chester W. Nimitz"
        },
        {
          "question": "1890 Alfred Mahan book that inspired the buildup of the US Navy.",
          "answer": "The Influence of Sea Power upon History, 1660-1783"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Vikings",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Specialized ship used by the Vikings to raid Europe.",
          "answer": "longship"
        },
        {
          "question": "Island discovered by an explorer called “the Red” after leaving Iceland.",
          "answer": "Greenland"
        },
        {
          "question": "Inscribed stones, often memorials, that were used by the Vikings.",
          "answer": "runestones"
        },
        {
          "question": "Explorer who established a Viking settlement, possibly in Newfoundland, around 1000 AD.",
          "answer": "Leif Erikson"
        },
        {
          "question": "Viking name for the settlement founded by that man on the coast of North America.",
          "answer": "Vinland"
        },
        {
          "question": "Archaeological site on the tip of Newfoundland, the possible site of that settlement.",
          "answer": "L’Anse aux Meadows"
        },
        {
          "question": "Federation ruled by the Rurik dynasty where Vikings served in the Varangian guard.",
          "answer": "Kievan Rus"
        },
        {
          "question": "Father of Cnut the Great who became the first Viking king of England.",
          "answer": "Sweyn Forkbeard"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Assassinations",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Country where King Faisal was killed in Riyadh.",
          "answer": "Saudi Arabia"
        },
        {
          "question": "Female British Prime Minister who was targeted in the Brighton Hotel bombing.",
          "answer": "Margaret Thatcher"
        },
        {
          "question": "Country where Park Hung-Chee was assassinated.",
          "answer": "South Korea"
        },
        {
          "question": "Common item used to inject Alexander Litvinenko with poison.",
          "answer": "umbrella"
        },
        {
          "question": "Roman Emperor whose assassination in 192 AD ended the Nerva-Antonine dynasty.",
          "answer": "Lucius Aurelius Commodus"
        },
        {
          "question": "Prime Minister of Israel who was killed in 1995.",
          "answer": "Yitzhak Rabin"
        },
        {
          "question": "First female Prime Minister of Pakistan who was killed while campaigning in 2007.",
          "answer": "Benazir Bhutto"
        },
        {
          "question": "City where Elisabeth of Austria was stabbed by an anarchist in 1898.",
          "answer": "Geneva"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This event led to the dispatch of a riverboat column under Charles Wilson that arrived two days late and a desert column that fought at Abu Klea. Rudolf von Slatin was shown the decapitated head of a general during this event. George W. Joy’s depiction of this event features a man (20 pts)",
        "staring at his watch as soldiers run up a set of stairs to spear him. William Gladstone’s nickname changed from G.O.M. to M.O.G. thanks to this event, in which (10 pts)",
        "Muhammad Ahmad’s dervishes beheaded Charles Gordon. For ten points, name this 1885 event in which the Mahdists seized Sudan’s capital."
      ],
      "answer": "Siege/Fall/etc. of Khartoum"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In this book’s epilogue, Professor James Pieixoto suggests that 20th-century overpopulation in India could have been controlled by a sterility virus while discussing the validity of cassette tapes used to record this text in the home of the (20 pts)",
        "Commander. With Aunt Elizabeth, this novel’s narrator helps Janine give birth and tries to find her friend Moira, who successfully flees the (10 pts)",
        "Republic of Gilead. Mike Pence has been protested by women wearing costumes from, for ten points, what novel by Margaret Atwood narrated by Offred, a fertile woman with the title role?"
      ],
      "answer": "The Handmaid’s Tale"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This leader’s military was put under scrutiny after it attacked American journalists Amy Goodman and Allan Nairn and British cinematographer Max Stahl in the Santa Cruz Massacre. This leader tried to prevent Western influence from reaching his country by revamping his country’s policy of (20 pts)",
        "Pancasila. This ruler was granted power of his country in the Supersemar Decree, which was ordered following the 30th of September Movement. This ruler’s (10 pts)",
        "New Order government opposed his predecessor’s Guided Democracy, and he jailed that predecessor’s daughter, Megawati. For ten points, name this Indonesian president who invaded East Timor and succeeded Sukarno."
      ],
      "answer": "Suharto"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In this modern-day state, Edmund Fanning and Francis Nash faced corruption charges from a group that fought William Tryon at the Battle of Alamance. The Great Awakening inspired a farmer from this state, Herman Husband, to create the anti-colonial (20 pts)",
        "Regulator Movement. The word “Croatoan” inscribed in a tree was allegedly the only clue of what happened to the (10 pts)",
        "Roanoke Colony in this state. Charles I inspired the name of, for ten points, what state whose capital is named after Walter Raleigh?"
      ],
      "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A religion that developed in this country exclusively uses oral tradition and syncretizes the Orishas of Yoruban belief with the vodun of West Africa. That faith of this country, Candombl´e, is practiced by the povo de santo and incorporates aspects of (20 pts)",
        "Roman Catholicism, this country’s majority religion. A 100-foot-tall (10 pts)",
        "statue of Christ overlooks a city in this country that hosts the world’s largest pre-Lenten Carnival. For ten points, name this country where the Cristo Redentor statue stands in Rio de Janeiro."
      ],
      "answer": "Brazil"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A holder of this position investigated the 1967 Detroit race riot as the leader, and namesake, of the Kerner Commission. In 2003, a holder of this position was indicted on corruption charges relating to (20 pts)",
        "“Operation Safe Road.” George Ryan was a holder of this position, that had earlier been held by Dwight Green until the election of a man who lost to (10 pts)",
        "Dwight Eisenhower in back-to-back Presidential elections. Adlai Stevenson II held, for ten points, what position that often clashes with the Mayor of Chicago from Springfield?"
      ],
      "answer": "Governor of Illinois"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The Arajs Kommando, a fascist paramilitary group from this nation, perpetrated the Rumbula Massacre here. This modern day nation was once the Duchy of Courland, a realm annexed by Russia in the Third Partition of Poland. Karlis Ulmanis led this country for much of the inter-war period, including after a (20 pts)",
        "1934 coup in which he dissolved the Saeima parliament. This country controls the southern portion of the historical region of (10 pts)",
        "Livonia. For ten points, name this Baltic nation that gained independence from the USSR in the Singing Revolution with its neighbors, Estonia and Lithuania."
      ],
      "answer": "Latvia"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Soldiers on the losing side at this battle were given until the 25th of August to surrender in exchange for a full pardon. The Duke of Schomberg was among the leaders of the winning side killed at this battle, which was followed by the Declaration of (20 pts)",
        "Finglas. One side fled to Limerick following this battle, where they successfully fended off a siege. (10 pts)",
        "Dutch Blue Guards were employed by the winning side of this battle fought near a namesake river. For ten points, name this 1690 victory for William of Orange, after which James II fled the British Isles."
      ],
      "answer": "Battle of the Boyne"
    }
  ]
}